[
    {
        "question": "A _____ is an example of a systems program.",
        "options": ["command interpreter", "Web browser", "text formatter", "database system"],
        "answer": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "If a program terminates abnormally, a dump of memory may be examined by a ____ to determine the cause of the problem.",
        "options": ["module", "debugger", "shell", "control card"],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "A message-passing model is ____.",
        "options": [
            "easier to implement than a shared memory model for intercomputer communication",
            "faster than the shared memory model",
            "a network protocol, and does not apply to operating systems",
            "only useful for small simple operating systems"
        ],
        "answer": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "A microkernel is a kernel ____.",
        "options": [
            "containing many components that are optimized to reduce resident memory size",
            "that is compressed before loading in order to reduce its resident memory size",
            "that is compiled to produce the smallest size possible when stored to disk",
            "that is stripped of all nonessential components"
        ],
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "A boot block ____.",
        "options": [
            "typically only knows the location and length of the rest of the bootstrap program",
            "typically is sophisticated enough to load the operating system and begin its execution",
            "is composed of multiple disk blocks",
            "is composed of multiple disk cylinders"
        ],
        "answer": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "_____ provide(s) an interface to the services provided by an operating system.",
        "options": ["Shared memory", "System calls", "Simulators", "Communication"],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "_____ allow operating system services to be loaded dynamically.",
        "options": ["Virtual machines", "Modules", "File systems", "Graphical user interfaces"],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "Microkernels use _____ for communication.",
        "options": ["message passing", "shared memory", "system calls", "virtualization"],
        "answer": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "The Windows CreateProcess() system call creates a new process. What is the equivalent system call in UNIX:",
        "options": ["dish()", "spoon()", "fork()", "knife()"],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "Android runs Java programs _____________",
        "options": [
            "in the Dalvik virtual machine.",
            "natively.",
            "in the Java virtual machine.",
            "Android does not run Java programs."
        ],
        "answer": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "_____ is/are not a technique for passing parameters from an application to a system call.",
        "options": ["Cache memory", "Registers", "Stack", "Special block in memory"],
        "answer": 0
    }
]
